Carlos Pambo

Technical Team Lead at GGI Inc.

Montréal, QC, Canada

 \Box +1 (514) 891-5177

□ carlos.pambo@hotmail.com

GitHub | In LinkedIn

Bio

A technical lead, software architect and engineer with over 9 years of experience. Skilled in agile software development methodologies, data science, machine learning, solutions and software components architecture, databases, backend services and integration development of web services, micro-services, data pipelines and operationalisation of machine learning models in public (AWS) and private cloud platforms.

Possesses technical and leadership skills demonstrated across multiple industries, including banking, financial and related services, telecommunications, logistics, media and advertisement, travel and tourism, and automotive.

PhD (Computer Engineering) candidate at Polytechnique Montréal under Dr. Bentley Oakes. Researching application of AI computer vision methods in cyber-physical digital twins (DT) systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CGI Inc. (CA)

Technical Team Lead

June 2023 to Present

Technical Lead at CGI's telecommunications and media business unit. Consults at Bell Canada on the content discovery and data ingestion pipeline solutions project. Responsible for identifying requirements, developing design structures, and coordinating with the project lead to review timelines and technical deliverables. He analyses ongoing projects and writes progress reports for all the involved stakeholders. Leads a team of 10 that includes software engineers, business analysis and QA engineers. Oversees their performance in the projects. Conducted security and performance audits and system modifications for the development team, senior managers, and the respective product owners.

BMW Group (ZA)

Solutions Architect Aug. 2022 to May 2023

Solutions architect at BMW Group's financial services business unit for the digital checkout solution and trade-in products to be used at BMW Group's future sales model program.

Senior Software Engineer

Jun. 2021 to Jul. 2022

Senior software engineer at BMW Group's financial services business unit, building the DCS product ecosystem. DCS is a configurable solution that enables BMW's suppliers and buyers interested in buying any of the BMW's branded (BMW, MINI, Motorrad, etc.) vehicles, parts or components in their respective markets. The product is currently deployed in more than 26 markets in Asia, Europe and Australasia. Integrating with different dealers and payment processors through BMW's own bank and payment services until I was promoted to **Solutions Architect**.

Entelect (ZA)

Senior Software Engineer

Jan. 2020 to May 2021

Senior software engineer consultant at Discovery S.A, at the group's information systems business unit on Discovery's financial advisor zone platform team.

Xpedia Applications (ZA)

Senior Software Engineer

Jul. 2019 to Dec. 2019

Worked on the custom software development department, a list of the client's systems worked on, including, but not limited to, SPSI's integrated country engine (ICE) platform.

ResRequest (ZA)

Integrated Systems Developer

Worked in the software development department, part of the systems maintenance team, ensuring that ResRequest client's API connections to and from ResRequest servers are running.

Rocvest Group (ZA)

Software Engineer

Jul. 2014 to May. 2018

Worked as an offshoring consultant at various company projects, including Bottle's alcohol delivery app (rebranded to Pick n' Pay ASAP!; Health45 patient management platform; Beedhub delivery team, to mention a few, during his tenure there.

EDUCATION

Polytechnique Montréal (Montréal, CA)

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD): Computer Engineering

Sept. 2024 (In-progress)

Stellenbosch University (Stellenbosch, ZA)

Master of Engineering (MEng): Industrial Engineering (Data Science)

Jan. 2022 to Jul. 2023 (Cum laude)

Thesis: An Evolutionary Algorithm for the Vehicle Routing Problem with Drones with Interceptions (VRPDi).

Regent Business School (Johannesburg, ZA)

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A)

Jan. 2018 to Jul. 2019

Thesis: Exploring the Effects of Mergers and Acquisitions on Employee Job Satisfaction: A Case Study of Reservations Request Inc., KwaZulu-Natal.

Postgraduate Diploma: Operations Management

Jan. 2017 to Dec. 17

Tshwane University of Technology (Pretoria, ZA)

Bachelor of Technology (BTech): Information Technology (Intelligent Systems)

Jan. 2012 to Jul. 2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Spoken Languages: Portuguese (Native), English (Excellent), French (Limited working proficiency)

Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript/Typescript

Developer Tools: Jira, Git (Bitbucket, GitHub, GitLab), Docker, Postman, Insomnia, ELK, TIBCO, Redis, Swagger (OpenAPI)

Frameworks: Spring, Quarkus, JPA, Hibernate, Terraform, Angular2+, Node.JS, Django, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Keras Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB

Cloud Technologies: AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, DynamoDB, Lambda, Elastic Cache, SQS, Athena, MSK, ECS, etc.), GCP (Compute Engine, BigQuery, etc.), Kafka

Soft Skills: Empathic leadership; Excellent communicator; Dependable; Critical thinker; Problem solver; Team worker;

Areas of Interest: Artificial intelligence (deep learning, machine learning, computer vision); Systems modelling; Programming; Politics and economics; Sports

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS & CERTIFICATES

Institute of Information Technology Professionals South Africa (IITPSA)

Oct. 2017

Deep Learning by DeepLearning.AI on Coursera

Nov. 2023

DeepLearning.AI TensorFlow Developer by DeepLearning.AI on Coursera

Nov. 2023

REFERENCES

Available upon request.